A Finding Aid to the Nell Blaine letters to Robert A. Wilson, 1962-2010, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Nell Blaine letters to Robert A. Wilson
1962-2010
Archives of American Art
Blaine, Nell, 1922-1996
AAA.blainell2
Archival Resource Key
0.6 Linear feet
The letters from artist Nell Blaine and her friend New York bookseller Robert A. Wilson measure 0.6 linear feet and date from 1962 to 2010. Additional material includes scattered business records, photographs, printed material, and a typescript of Blaine's journal.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Access to original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center.
Scope and Contents
The letters from artist Nell Blaine and her friend New York bookseller Robert A. Wilson measure 0.6 linear feet and date from 1962 to 2010. Additional material includes scattered business records, photographs, printed material, and a typescript of Blaine's journal.
Biographical / Historical
Nell Blaine (1922-1996) was a painter, printmaker, and illustrator active in New York City, New York.
Robert A. Wilson (1922-2016) was a bookseller and owner of Phoenix Book Shop in New York City, New York.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated in 1997 by Robert A. Wilson.
Arrangement
Due to the small size of this collection the papers are arranged as one series.
Related Materials
The Archives of American Art also holds the Nell Blaine Papers, 1942-1985, and an oral history interviews with Blaine conducted 1967 June 15, by Dorothy Seckler, for the Archives of American Art.
Painters -- New York (State) -- New York; Printmakers -- New York (State) -- New York; Illustrators -- New York (State) -- New York; Women artists; Women painters; Women printmakers; Diaries; Wilson, Robert A.; Phoenix Book Shop
- Nell Blaine Letters to Robert A. Wilson, 1962-2010; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 1-2
  Scope and Contents
  Found are letters written by Nell Blaine to her friend Robert Wilson dating from 1962 to 1997. Some letters are written on the back of exhibition announcements and also include holiday cards. Also found is a letter from Wilson to the Archives of American Art in 2010. Other scattered records include business records from Blaine's purchases from Wilson's bookstore; two photographs of Blaine's studio; printed material including clippings and exhibition announcements and catalogs; and a typescript of Blaine's 1967 journal.
  - Business Records, 1967-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1997, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Envelopes, circa 1970-circa 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Printed Material, Clippings, 1970-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Printed Material, Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1973-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Printed Material, Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1973-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Typescript, Nell Blaine's Journal (1967), circa 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)